Animation Number 1
（暦(こよみ)）はっ…
This isn't Hanekawa's room, is it?
（暦）
ここは 羽川(はねかわ)の部屋じゃないのか？
（月火(つきひ)）フッ フッ フッ♪
フフフ♪
フッ フッ フッ フッ フフフ♪
（月火）
あっ お兄ちゃん
おかえ… おお！
Onii-chan, welcome h—
There were at least six rooms there.
（暦）
部屋の数は６つはあった
But in that house,
なのに あの家には 羽川家には
in Hanekawa's house,
Hanekawa Tsubasa did not have a room.
羽川 翼(つばさ)の部屋がなかったのだ
Hanekawa, it's hopeless!
羽川 もうダメだろ あれは！
どうにもならないだろ？
It's completely hopeless!
修正不可能だ
It can't be rectified.
ひと言で言えば狂っている
It was, in a word, insane.
That house, that family, that household...
あの家は あの家族は あの家庭は
It was beyond finished, it was done for!
既に終わりすぎるほどに
終わっている！
You're so hopeless, Onii-chan.
もう しかたないな お兄ちゃんは
There, there. Was it scary?
よし よし 怖かったんだね
Here, go ahead.
はい いいよ
Gross!
（暦）気持ち悪い！
Is that any way to react to your sister's dedication for you?!
妹の献身に対して
何をするのよ お兄ちゃん！
It's educational guidance for you!
教育的指導だ！
You two have relied on the spur of the moment far too often!
お前たち姉妹は どれだけ
その場のノリで生きてるんだよ！
I can't help it! I'm your sister after all!
しょうがないじゃん
お兄ちゃんの妹だし！
You really had us worried, though.
（月火）それにしても心配したよ
You didn't come home at all.
お兄ちゃん
全然 帰ってこないからさ
Karen-chan and I were afraid that you might've been attacked by a monster.
（月火）
ひょっとしたらお化けにでも
行き合ったんじゃないかって
火憐(かれん)ちゃんと２人で
心配していたんだよ
A monster?
お化け？
う〜ん お化けっていうか
化け猫なんだけど
A cat monster, to be precise.
A cat monster?
化け… 猫
Yeah.
（月火）
うん まだウワサの段階だから
何とも言えないんだけど
It's still just a rumor so I can't say for sure yet,
but apparently this humanoid cat monster is going around town attacking people.
人の姿をした猫のお化けが
街のあちこちで
人を襲っているんだって
Energy Drain
Animation Number 110
When did that start?
（暦）それは いつからの話だ？
I first heard the rumor earlier today.
（月火）
私のところにウワサが
入ってきたのは
今日の昼間のことだよ
That's why I got so worried about you and kept calling you like mad.
だからお兄ちゃんのことが
心配になって
そこから鬼のように
電話をかけたんだもん
I was really relieved when I saw that you hadn't fallen victim to it,
お兄ちゃんが
被害に遭ってなかったことには
胸をなで下ろしたけれど
but for a case like this, there's no way that the
Fire Sisters, avatars of justice, can just sit around idly!
だけど この事態 正義感の権化
ファイヤーシスターズとしては
黙りあぐねるね
Karen-chan is already making
preparations to hunt the monster now.
火憐ちゃんも今 化け猫狩りの
準備をしているところだよ
Uh...
（暦）いや
（月火）うん？
What's wrong, Onii-chan?
お兄ちゃん どうしたの？
What is it?
いやって何？
Well, I mean...
いや〜 それは…
That wouldn't be good.
困ったなと思ってさ
I was scared enough riding my bike back home in the dark,
夜道を自転車で帰ってくるだけで
こんなに怖かったというのに
そんな怖い化け猫の怪談を
聞かされてしまっては
so if you leave a coward like me at home alone
after telling me a scary story about a cat monster,
もう完璧 ぶるっちゃって
there's no way I'll be able to sleep.
チキンな僕は
１人じゃ寝れねえよ
So I was thinking maybe the three of us could sleep in the same bed for the next few nights.
だから今日から しばらく
火憐ちゃんと月火ちゃんに
添い寝してもらおうと
思っていたけれど
Of course, I won't stop you if you must leave for the sake of justice,
いや 正義のために
出陣しなければ
ならないんだとすれば
but you're the only ones I can rely on.
そりゃ 諦めるしかないな
お前たちだけが 頼りだったんだが
What?
なに！ 私たちだけが頼り？
We're the only ones you can rely on?
Guess there's no choice then!
だったらしかたないな〜
I can't leave such a helpless brother alone
like that, so I'll convince Karen-chan to stay.
ビビリのお兄ちゃんが
かわいそうだから
火憐ちゃんは
私が説得してあげるよ
化け猫退治は お巡りさんに任そう
We'll leave hunting the cat monster to the police!
Thanks.
ありがとう
Animation Number 126
Never mind the meddlecat's ability to energy drain on touch, I don't even know what its goal is.
（暦）
手当たりしだいの
エナジードレインといい
障(さわ)り猫(ねこ)の目的が分からない
Though, I'm not sure if I even have the right to know.
だが 僕にそれを知る権利が
あるのだろうか
Do I even want to know in the first place?
それ以前に 僕はそれを
知りたいと思っているのだろうか
I snuck into Hanekawa's house, invaded their privacy, and ended up completely flustered.
羽川家に不法侵入して
あの家の内情を知ってしまって
あれほど取り乱した僕が
There really are things in this world that
we're better off not knowing, aren't there?
知らなくてもいいことって
世の中には
やっぱりあるんじゃないか
If you're going to create a fantasy then shatter that illusion yourself,
勝手に憧れて
勝手に幻滅するくらいなら
maybe it's better if you hadn't known from the start.
最初から知るべきじゃ
ないんじゃないのか
Maybe I shouldn't have stuck my nose into her life back then.
あのとき 僕はやっぱり
羽川に深入りするべきじゃ
なかったんじゃないのか
Maybe I should've ignored the gauze.
ガーゼのことなんか気にせずに
But wouldn't that be just like wanting to have my cake and eat it too?
でもさ それって つまりは
おいしいとこ取りってことだよな
Like having only love, expectations, and admiration for her,
好きでいて 期待して
憧れていたいだけ
despite receiving so much help from her over spring break.
自分は春休みに
あれだけ助けてもらっておいて
I still didn't know after giving it a lot of thought.
いくら考えても分からなかった
The one thing that's clear is that
I knew absolutely nothing about her.
はっきりしていることが
あるとすれば
僕は彼女のことを 何にも
知らなかったということである
To claim that it was love was absurd.
これで恋とか バカげている
It's embarrassing to recall my conversation with Tsukihi after all that has happened.
月火と交わしたあの会話が
こうなってしまうと
やけに恥ずかしかった
But...
だけど それでも今でも
Even so, whenever I think of Hanekawa, my chest tightens.
僕は羽川のことを思うと
胸が はちきれそうなんだけれどな
1st May
Hanekawa didn't come to school on the first or second of May.
５月１日は… そして
５月２日も
羽川は学校には来なかった
Saturday      2nd May
By the time class was over on the second, rumors of the cat monster had already spread throughout the school.
２日の放課後が
近づいてくるころには
Naoetsu Private High School
化け猫のウワサは
学校中に広がっていて
Many students had seen it firsthand.
目撃談も 多数 含まれていた
You can imagine how active the meddlecat was.
障り猫のご活躍ぶりが うかがえた
With the next set of consecutive holidays beginning on the third of May,
翌日の５月３日から
再び始まる連休を前に
I decided to visit Oshino at the
abandoned building once more.
僕はもう一度
忍野(おしの)の住まう廃ビルを
訪ねておくことにした
O-Oshino!
（暦）おっ 忍野！
（忍野）おっ いやあ 阿良々木(あららぎ)君
Yo, Araragi-kun.
I've been waiting.
待ちかねたよ
I figured you'd show up soon.
そろそろ来るんじゃないかと
思っていたんだが
Though I had hoped to have recovered before then.
それまでには
回復しておきたかったんだけどね
I used the miracle bandage on you the other day, you see.
霊験あらたかな包帯は
こないだ阿良々木君に
使っちゃったからなあ
Oshino, what on Earth happened?
（暦）
忍野 一体 何があったんだ？
What happened?
（忍野）
何があったって？ 別に何もないさ
Nothing much.
I lost, that's all.
ただ負けただけでね
Y-You lost? To what?
（暦）ま… 負けたって 何に？
Isn't it obvious?
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
（忍野）決まっているさ
障り猫にね
To the meddlecat.
Starting from April 30th, it's been a little less than 3 days.
４月30日の夜から数えて
足かけ３日
In that time I've battled it 20 times
それだけの間に
20回ほどバトルになって
and lost 20 times.
20回ほど負けた
So you lost every battle?
それって全敗じゃねえか
Every battle.
（忍野）全敗だよ 見る影もない
Pretty bad, huh?
アッハッハッ
An old man like me has no chance fighting against a high school girl in underwear.
まったく
女子高生の下着姿なんてのは
おじさんには目の毒だね
I was so distracted that you couldn't even call it a battle.
そっちに気を取られちまって
まるでバトルになりゃしない
Geez...
（忍野）ったく
So don't you try to squeeze anything more out of this soft, listless, and shriveled up old man.
こんな精も根も尽き果てて
枯れちまってる中年のおっさんから
精力を搾り取るなよなあ
I-Is the meddlecat really such a powerful aberration?
（暦）
そ… そこまでの怪異(かいい)なのかよ
障り猫って
Strong enough to walk all over a specialist like you?
専門家のお前さえも
圧倒するほどの…
No, not really.
いいや そんなことはないよ
I told you last time, didn't I?
この間も ちらっと言ったけどさ
It's nothing compared to the vampire that attacked you.
阿良々木君が襲われた吸血鬼
なんかには及ぶべくもない
It's so low-level that even the act of comparing the two is ridiculous.
つうか 比べること自体が
不遜なくらいの低級怪異だ
Wait, you said that it's not on the same level as a vampire,
吸血鬼に比べて
格差があるとは言ったけれど
but you didn't say that the meddlecat was a low-level aberration.
障り猫が低級怪異だなんて
お前は この間 言ってなかったぞ
If I had told you that, you'd undoubtedly want to help.
（忍野）
そこまで教えちゃえば
だったら じゃあ自分も手伝うとか
阿良々木君が
言い出しかねなかったから
That's why I didn't explain that far.
そこまでは説明しなかっただけ
In truth, it's so low-level that even an amateur who tries his best has a chance to defeat it.
素人でも知恵の絞り様(よう)では
対処のできる類いの
実はそんな程度の怪異だ
（暦）えっ でも…
But...
Of course, I didn't hold back just because of that.
（忍野）
もちろん 僕はだからといって
手を抜いたりはしなかったよ
I faced it with all my strength.
本気で挑んだ
But I lost.
だけど負けた
The meddlecat is small fry.
障り猫は雑魚だ
路上で死んだふりをして
同情して寄ってきた人間に取りつく
It plays dead on the road, then possesses any human who approaches it out of sympathy.
It's a substitution-type monster.
入れ代わり系のお化け
体を乗っ取るタイプの怪異
An aberration that takes over its host.
And just like a God of Poverty,
it brings great misfortune to its host.
そして貧乏神のごとく
体の持ち主を 本体を
不幸のどん底に たたき落とす
In that sense, it's a very typical kind of monster.
言ってしまえば よくある
テンプレートなお化けなんだよ
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
But the fact that it possessed the Class Rep
makes this an almost impossibly irregular case.
だけど 取りつかれたのが
委員長ちゃんだっていうのが
この場合は ありえないほどの
イレギュラーだった
What should've been nothing but small fry
本来 雑魚にすぎなかった障り猫を
ほとんど最強に近い
has transformed into something so strong that it might even rival a vampire in strength.
下手をすれば
吸血鬼にさえ匹敵する怪異にまで
引っ張り上げている
It's the sharing of her knowledge,
not her body, that makes it so dangerous.
肉体を共有していることよりも
知識を共有しているというのが
マズいね
All my ancient aberration countermeasures — my techniques and methods —
僕の使う古式ゆかしい怪異対策が
手法が 方法が
she was able to counter all of them perfectly.
物の見事に
全部 跳ね返されちまう
She's familiar with all my specialist knowledge.
専門家張りの専門知識を
彼女は持ち合わせている
あの子は何でも知ってるよ
That girl knows everything.
I've never even heard of an aberration that uses strategy and tactics to attack before.
戦略と戦術を持って
人を襲う怪異なんて
そんなの聞いたことねえや
I was aware of it from the start,
but the Class Rep is no ordinary girl.
最初から
分かっていたことではあるけれど
やっぱり ただ者じゃなかったね
委員長ちゃんは
The skill with which she attacks people is nothing like a normal aberration.
人を襲う際の手際の良さといい
怪異のやることじゃないよ
Wait a second.
（暦）ちょっと待てよ
The skill with which she attacks people?
人を襲う際の手際の良さ？
Oshino, are you telling me
Hanekawa's actively attacking people?
忍野 それじゃ羽川が
まるで積極的に
人を襲ってるみたいじゃないか！
Well, you could say that.
（忍野）まあ そうなんだろうね
障り猫は
そういう怪異じゃないはずなのに
The meddlecat isn't supposed to be like that.
However, Araragi-kun, the fact that I've had such a hard time so far might actually be good news.
ただ 阿良々木君
僕がここまで苦戦するというのは
実は そう悪い展開でも
ないのかもしれないよ
You could say that this proves the
Class Rep is still inside there somewhere.
この展開は 障り猫の中に
委員長ちゃんが残っていることの
証明とも言えるんだ
That's what I think.
僕はそう思っているよ
At the very least, if the meddlecat had taken over
her body and knowledge and removed her entirely,
少なくとも障り猫の中に
委員長ちゃんがおらず
things wouldn't have come to this.
肉体も知識も
完全に乗っ取られているならば
こういう展開にはならない
It's likely that the Class Rep's consciousness is still largely intact in there.
多分 障り猫の中には
委員長ちゃんの意識が
かなり膨大に残っている
That's why it's such a formidable opponent.
だからこそ 手ごわい
At this point, this information comes as both incredibly bad and slightly hopeful news.
これは今のところ
最悪の情報であると同時に
救いのある情報でもある
How? What hope do we have?
（暦）
どうして どこに
救いがあるっていうんだよ
Well, if she had been completely
taken over, there'd be no way out.
（忍野）
いや だって完全に乗っ取られたら
もう おしまいだからさ
I'd have no choice but to kill her.
殺すしかなくなる
We must salvage what remains of the
Class Rep's consciousness while it's still there.
委員長ちゃんの意識が
残っているうちに
その意識をサルベージしないと
We have to exterminate the cat monster.
化け猫を退治してしまわないと
If we don't, your friend Hanekawa Tsubasa will completely disappear from this world.
羽川 翼という
阿良々木君の大事なお友達は
この世から完全に
失われてしまうというわけさ
Animation Number 212
A white cat lies dead by the road.
（暦）
路上で白い猫が死んでいる
Feeling pity for it, a man passing by
buries it and offers a prayer.
そんな猫をかわいそうに思い
道行く男の一人が その猫を埋め
手を合わせてやったという
That night, the kind man begins to act strangely.
その夜から
善良なるその男の奇行が始まる
Unable to cope with him, his friends and family call for a priest to exorcise the cat.
これでは手に負えないと
降参した周囲の者は
たまらず祈祷師(きとうし)を呼んで
取りついた猫を
はらおうとするけれど
And here's the twist—the true face of the meddlecat.
ここからがオチ
障り猫の真骨頂
The kind man was never possessed by a cat in the first place.
善良なる彼には
元々 猫なんて
取りついてはいなかったのだという
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
You can call the ending absurd or surprising, but that was a story of an aberration with a bit of a moral.
不条理オチというか
びっくりオチというか
これは いささか
教訓じみた怪異譚(たん)でね
There is no such thing as a truly kind human,
and any compassion is merely skimming the surface.
善良なだけの人間なんて
存在するはずがなく
優しさなんてのは とどのつまりは
上っ面の上澄みにすぎない
The opposite is sure to lurk beneath.
必ずその裏がある
If there is light, there is darkness.
光があれば闇があり
白があれば黒がある
If there is white, there is black.
It's a story of a man's true nature revealed.
人間の裏側を見透かすような
エピソードなんだ
But why a cat?
（暦）でも どうして猫なんだ？
Because cats are natural hypocrites.
（忍野）
そりゃ 猫ってのは
“かぶる”もんだからさ
And the Class Rep's been doing what cats do best.
委員長ちゃんだって
猫をかぶっていたということだろう
It means that there's nobody who's truly honest and just.
善良で公平なだけの人間なんて
いないということさ
Having to continuously keep up appearances may have been why she accumulated so much stress.
むしろ そうであろうと
し続けるからこそ
ストレスがたまるんだ
To the point of utter blackness.
黒々とね
Still, playing the cat doesn't normally go beyond hiding behind a mask.
それでも普通 猫は
あくまでも仮面なんだけど
どういうことなのか
I don't know why, but the Class Rep and the meddlecat seem to have merged into one.
委員長ちゃんは ほとんど
障り猫と 一体化しちまってる
Since the cat is the default form, I suppose
it's more of an assimilation than a merging.
猫のほうが本体となれば
一体化というより同化かな
A truly formidable opponent.
全く強敵だよ
Or should I say invincible?
これも強敵というよりは
無敵だろうね
I have to go finish it off, or things will get worse.
さっさと ケリをつけちまわないと
とにかくヤバい
It's possible we'll find out at the end that the
Class Rep was never possessed by a cat to begin with.
それこそ最終的に
委員長ちゃんには元々
猫なんて取りついてはいなかった
なんてオチになりかねないぜ
This must be dealt with before the Class Rep and meddlecat become one and the same.
委員長ちゃんと猫とが
完全に融合しちまう前に
どうにかしないと
3rd May: Constitution Memorial Day
ＨＩＧＨ ＳＣＨＯＯＬ
ＣＲＯＳＳＩＮＧ
Naoetsu Private High School
I
II
III
IV
V
VI
VII
VIII
Red Scene
Animation Number "None"
This is the desk that Hanekawa-san always rests her huge boobs on...
（暦）
実は巨乳の羽川さんのお胸様が
いつもこの机に
押しつけられているんだよなあ
You are an immyeasurable pervert.
（障り猫）
お前は限度額のない変態かにゃ
Scary, meow.
怖いにゃ 怪異より怖いにゃ
Scarier than an aberration.
You just got excited from licking a girl's desk.
お前は今 女子の机を
ペロペロにゃめて興奮していたにゃ
N-No, I didn't—
（暦）いっ いや 違う！
M-More importantly, where did you
come from and how did you get in here?
そっ そんなことよりお前
どこから どうやって
この教室に入った？
（障り猫）
そんにゃことよりって 人間
Myore importantly?
Humyan, are you saying there's a myore important myatter here than you licking my myaster's desk?
お前がご主人の机を
にゃめ回していたこと以上の事件が
この世にあるのかにゃ？
（暦）
何のことだか
さっぱり分からないな
I have no idea what you're talking about!
Say what you will, but I won't admit anything in court!
僕は お前が何を言おうと
裁判じゃ何も認めないぞ！
Myahahahaha
（障り猫）ニャハハハハ…
Oh?
あっ にゃんだ？
You seem to have nyo intention of fighting, humyan.
敵意のにゃさそうにゃ
ツラだにゃ〜 人間
It's not like I could lay a finger on you in the first place, cat.
（暦）
どうせ僕じゃ お前をどうこうは
できないからな
猫 それに命まで
取られるわけじゃない だろ？
Besides, it's not like you'd kill me, right?
Who knyows?
さて どうかにゃ
My enyergy drain is a character trait, nyot a skill.
俺のエニャジードレインは
スキルじゃにゃくて
キャラ設定だからにゃ
I can't control it.
自分でコントロール
できるわけじゃにゃい
I can try to hold back but I can't adjust its strength.
手加減はできても
加減はきかにゃい
I might kill you by mistake even though I'm nyot trying to.
殺すつもりが にゃくっても
うっかり殺してしまう
ということも ありうるにゃ
それでも出会い頭に
かみつかれたり
Still, it's good that you didn't just bite and scratch me the moment we met.
ひっかかれたりしないだけ
ましってもんだ
そんなことをされちゃ
ひとたまりもないからな
I wouldn't have lasted a second.
A vyampire, huh?
フン 吸血鬼か
Nyormally I'd be no myatch against such a high-level aberration,
Myahahahaha
Vampire
まっ 俺にゃんかじゃ
本来 太刀打ちもできない—
上等にゃ怪異だにゃ
だけど
ご主人の戦術と戦略のおかげで
but with my myaster's strategy and tactics, I was able to take out even a professionyal with ease.
プロフェッショニャルの専門家さえ
圧倒できるほどの存在力を
得ることができた
I couldn't be myore grateful.
ありがたいもんにゃ
I don't repay any favors.
俺は恩返しをしにゃい
In fact, I'm an aberration that returns favors by doing harm,
むしろ恩をあだで返すタイプの
怪異にゃんだけど
これに限っちゃ
but in this case I'm so grateful that
I might even repay the favor, meow.
恩返しをしてもいいと思えるほどに
ありがたい話だにゃ
Vampire
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
ニャハハハハ！
Well, while energy drain is characteristic of both meddlecats and vampires,
（暦）
まあ エナジードレインを
特性に持つ者同士とはいっても
it serves completely different purposes for the two.
障り猫と吸血鬼じゃ
全然違うんだろうけどな
A vampire uses energy drain to feed, while a meddlecat's is a curse.
吸血鬼のエナジードレインは
“食事”であって
Feed
Animation Number 275
障り猫のエナジードレインは
“呪い”
Curse
Animation Number 275
フン まあ そうにゃ
True enyough.
What I don't get is why you're
indiscriminately attacking people.
（暦）ただ 分かんねえのは
お前が無差別に
人を襲ってるってところなんだよ
If we're talking about types of aberrations,
meddlecats were never the kind to attack people.
タイプって話をするなら
障り猫ってのは そもそも
人を襲うタイプの
怪異じゃないんだろう？
Hey, cat.
おい 猫 お前
You...
Huh?
（障り猫）
にゃ〜に ただの憂さ晴らしにゃよ
It's nyothing but a distraction.
（暦）はあ？
（障り猫）人を襲ってる理由
I attack people for entertainmyent.
ただの憂さ晴らし
Like a ring-and-run, or wall graffiti.
ピンポンダッシュとか
壁に落書きとか
It's the same idea.
そうゆうのと同(おにゃ)じ
It's just to relieve stress.
ストレスの発散にゃ
Relieve stress?
ストレスの発散だって？
それ えっ ちょっと
どういう意味だ？
Wait, what do you mean?
Nyothing myore and nyothing less.
（障り猫）
どういう意味も こういう意味も
そのまんまの意味だにゃ
I myeant exactly what I said.
お前さ あの家(うち)の中(にゃか) 見たんだろ？
You looked inside that house, right?
What house?
（暦）あの家って？
My myaster's house.
（障り猫）ご主人の家だにゃ
I knyow you were there.
分かってんだよ
Cats have a rather keen sense of smyell.
猫ってのは そこそこ
鼻(はにゃ)も利くんだにゃ
When I came back to change,
the house was filled with your scent.
着替えに帰ってみりゃよ
家ん中じゅうが
お前のにおいで満ちてたぜ
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Myaster lived in that house with that family for 15 years.
あんにゃ家で あんにゃ家庭で
15年間 ご主人は過ごしたんにゃ
It's easy to imyagine how much pressure she's been suffering up until nyow.
それがどれほどの圧力とにゃって
ご主人を責めたてていたか
想像がつくだろう？
I was simply relieving that stress by playing some tricks on our kind neighbors, meow.
俺はそれを
その辺の善良にゃる市民に
イタズラを働くことで
発散しているんにゃ
That's all it was.
それだけのことにゃよ
これは障りとか呪いとか
そういうのを度外視しての行いにゃ
I paid no heed to whether it was
myeddling or a curse or anything like that.
You paid no heed?
（暦）度外視って
Do aberrations do that?
（暦）
怪異が そんなことを
するもんなのか？
As a possessive-type aberration,
I've taken over my myaster's body.
（障り猫）俺は憑依(ひょうい)系の怪異として
ご主人の体を乗っ取っている
In other words, I'm inhabiting her brain.
つまり脳髄を乗っ取っている
That's how I knyow what she went through in her 15 years with that family.
だからご主人が
どんにゃふうに あの家庭で
15年間過ごしてきたか知っている
And that's why I'm helping her out with her stress problem.
だからご主人のストレスの発散に
協力してやってるってわけにゃ
Even if that's the case, you didn't need to attack innocent bystanders.
（暦）だが それが理由なら
無関係の人を襲うなんてこと
しなくっても
Unfortunyately, I only knyow of this method.
（障り猫）
あいにく俺は このやり方しか
知らねえんでにゃ
Being bad is fun, meow!
悪事って楽しいからにゃ
I enjoy causing trouble for random people I don't knyow.
見も知らぬ他人が困るから
楽しいんだにゃ
It's neither rationyal nor irrationyal.
理屈じゃない へ理屈でもにゃい
At the very least, as her reverse and darker personyality,
少(すく)にゃくとも反転し
暗転した人格としての俺は
I've become myore well-rounded in a sense, don't you think?
多少にゃりとも
丸みを帯びていると
思わにゃいかい？
Compared to when I tore off your arm, that is.
お前の腕を引きちぎったときと
比べればよう
I do think that.
（暦）それは思ってたよ
Right?
（障り猫）だろう？
That myeans what I'm doing is effective.
つまり俺のやってることは
効果的ってことにゃ
So don't worry about it.
そういうことだから安心しろ
My myaster's stress will be gone after I attack anyother 500 people or so.
あと500人も襲えば
ご主人のストレス発散は終わる
Then my work as an aberration will be done, and with the favor repaid I shall disappear.
そうすりゃ
俺という怪異は役目を終え
恩返しを終えて消滅するんだにゃ
So tell that Aloha shirt guy to stay out of my way.
だから余計な邪魔をすんにゃって
あのアロハのおっさんに
伝えておけよ
I don't really get it, but he's trying to save my myaster, right?
よく分からんけど あのアロハ野郎
ご主人を助けたいんだろう？
Leave that job to me.
だったらそれは 俺に任せておけ
Why would you do that much for her?
（暦）
どうして お前が
そこまでするんだよ？
You're simply a malicious spirit
possessing Hanekawa, aren't you?
お前なんて
所詮は羽川に取りついた
悪霊でしかねえだろ？
You shouldn't have any reason to actively help her.
羽川のために
何かを能動的にする理由なんか
ないはずだ
I told you myany times already, didn't I?
さっきから何度(にゃんど)も言ってるだろ？
I'm returning the favor, against my nyature.
らしくもにゃい恩返しのため
Though that's a lie, meow.
というのは しかしウソにゃ
In truth, I have nyo reason to feel thankful to my myaster
そもそも 俺は実のところ
知識を与えてくれたこと
以外については
for anything but the knyowledge she's given me.
ご主人に恩を感じる理由が
にゃいんにゃ
（暦）えっ 何を言っているんだ？
What are you talking about?
路上で車にひかれて
死んでいるところを
Hanekawa buried you after you were
fatally injured from being hit by a car.
羽川に埋めてもらったじゃないか
Didn't you take advantage of her
sympathy and kindness back then?
その同情心や優しさに
お前はつけ込んだはずじゃ
なかったのか？
No, I didn't.
（障り猫）違うんだにゃ それが
It's true that's what it looked like from an observer's point of view.
確かに現象としては
それと同じことが起きた
Myaster saw me lying on the road, picked me up,
ご主人は道路に横たわる俺を
拾い上げ
took me all the way to a place with a wonderful view, and buried me.
見晴らしのいい場所まで移動し
俺を埋めた
What you saw with your eyes wasn't wrong, meow.
その認識自体に 間違いはにゃい
A cat's grave
Animation Number 333
My myaster didn't feel a shred of sympathy for me.
ご主人は あのとき
俺に全く同情してにゃんか
いにゃかった
She picked me off the road and buried me like it was part of her work routine.
ご主人は路上で死んでる俺を
まるで決まりきった
ルーチンワークのように
供養したんにゃ
She had nyo emotion at all.
全くの無感情にゃ
She felt nyo pity for me whatsoever.
俺のことを まるで
哀れんだりしていにゃかった
In other words, there was nyothing in her heart that I could exploit.
つまり俺のつけ込む隙にゃんて
本当は にゃかったんにゃ
But... Hanekawa...
（暦）いや でも 羽川は…
My myaster's only wish was to be a nyormal girl.
“普通の女(おんにゃ)の子であろう”
というのが
ご主人の唯一の願いにゃ
She saw a dead cat on the side of the road, so she buried it.
道端で死んでいる猫を見かけたら
埋めてあげる
That was clearly the right thing to do.
まあ これは
確かに正しいことにゃ
You could call it a rule.
法則と言ってもいい
方程式と言ってもいい
You could call it a formula.
My myaster simply followed that rule and formula.
だからその法則と方程式に
ご主人は従った
That's all it was, meow.
それだけのことにゃ
No normal person would ever follow that rule or formula.
（暦）普通なら
そんな法則とか方程式は
順守できるはずがないんだ
Even if they knew that it was the right and beautiful thing to do,
それが正しくも
美しい行為だと分かっていても
most people wouldn't think to bury a dead cat on the side of the road.
大抵のヤツは
野たれ死(じ)んでいる猫を
埋めてやろうとは思わない
Tsubasa Hanekawa
Animation Number 344
No, they might think it, but they wouldn't take action.
いや 思うかもしれない
だけど実行はしない
They wouldn't have the heart or the ability to do it.
心情的にも能力的にも
できるはずがない
But Hanekawa did it.
なのに羽川は それをやってのける
The normal girl that
Animation Number 345
Hanekawa will never be
could never do it.
Exactly. She did it.
（障り猫）
そう やってのける 無感情ににゃ
Without feeling anything.
She carried out the myoral directive without thinking, like a myachine.
何(にゃに)も思わにゃいまま
機械のように倫理を全うできる
I've been buried plenty of times, but I've nyever come across anything like this.
数々の供養をされてきた俺にも
それは物珍しくってにゃ
It was so dark
Animation Number 345
That's why...
だから
It was so black
Animation Number 346
I wanted to help her.
助けてやりたくにゃったのさ
CLASSROOM
Animation Number 346
Basically, it was on a whim.
要するに気まぐれだよ
Catlike, nyo?
猫っぽいだろ
Anyway, make sure you tell him.
じゃ ちゃんと伝えといてくれよ
あのアロハ野郎には
Tell that Aloha shirt guy to let a cat play her tricks.
猫のイタズラくらい
見逃せっつっとけ
I don't want to sue him for animyal abuse.
動物虐待で
訴えられたくにゃきゃよ
I'm letting him live, after all.
こっちは見逃してやってんだから
What do you mean?
（暦）どういう意味だよ
You knyow, don't you?
Animation Number 352
（障り猫）分かんだろ？
You knyow, don't you?
If I
Animation Number 353
If I—or rather, my myaster—really wanted to harm him,
俺が つうかご主人が
If I
or rather my myaster
Animation Number 353
really
Animation Number 354
本気で害をにゃすつもりに
にゃってりゃ
really
wanted to
harm him
あんにゃ野郎は最初の１回目で
殺せてるってこった
I would've killed him in our first battle.
I only went easy on him because she knows him.
知り合いだから 手 抜いて
戦ってやってるってことだよ
As for you...
お前は まあ別に
何もするつもりもねえみたいだが
Well, it doesn't look like you plan to do anything.
That's the right thing to do, meow.
まっ お前が正解だよ
ご主人のためを思うにゃら
何もしにゃいのが正解だ
If you really care about my myaster, then it's best that you do nyothing.
You don't want to die, do you?
取り立てて死にたいってわけじゃ
ねえんだろ？
Farewell.
あばよ
You can, well, stay alive and be happy.
お前は 何(にゃん)かこう
頑張って幸せに暮らせや 人間
Humyan.
Wait!
（暦）待て！
Huh?
If your goal is to relieve Hanekawa's stress, that's impossible.
羽川のストレス発散が
お前の目的だと言うなら
そんなのは無理だぞ
Why, meow?
（障り猫）ああ にゃんでだよ？
Because the source of Hanekawa's stress is her parents.
（暦）
だって そのストレスの大本は
羽川の両親にあるんだろう？
Even if you were able to relieve all of her stress, once she goes home, it'll just build up again.
たとえストレスが
全部 発散されたところで
そんなものは 家に帰れば
また蓄積されるだけだ
Even if you assault 500 innocent people...
500人の無関係の他人を襲おうと
Even if you release her stress for a straight month...
１か月間
ストレス発散し続けようと
You'll end up right where you started.
いつかは 元の木阿弥(もくあみ)だ
（障り猫）
ふ〜ん ああ そりゃそうだ
Yeah, that's right.
Then I'll just hurt them so bad that they'll
nyever want to go back to that home, meow.
だったら 二度と帰ってくる気に
にゃらにゃいように にゃるまで
こっちで痛めつけてやるだけにゃ
I won't stop with just with an enyergy drain next time.
今度は エニャジードレインじゃ
済ませにゃい
I'll fight domyestic violence with domyestic violence,
家庭内(にゃい)暴力には家庭内暴力で
答えてやるだけにゃ
if that is my myaster's wish.
それがご主人の望みにゃら
えっ そんなこと！
You can't!
Yes.
（障り猫）そっ それで正解にゃ
That's the right answer.
You'll be myeddled with the myoment you touch me.
触った瞬間 障りがある
That's why I'm called a myeddlecat.
だから障り猫
Don't come near.
寄るにゃ 指一本触れるにゃ
Don't so myuch as touch me.
Staying out of this is the right answer.
関わりも持たにゃいのが正解にゃ
For me, and likely,
俺に対しても
そして多分
for my myaster.
ご主人に対しても… にゃ
Cat, you're...
猫… お前は！
Farewell. Live and be happy.
（障り猫）
あばよ お前は幸せに暮らせ
It's no good.
（暦）ダメだ
I really do love Hanekawa.
僕はやっぱり
羽川のことが好きだ
I love her so much that I simply can't touch her.
好きすぎて
とてもじゃねえけど触れねえ
あいつが好きだ
I love her.
好きかなって思って
I wondered if I loved her.
I felt I loved her.
好きだなって感じて
And I know I love her.
好きだって分かる
But it's just as Tsukihi-chan said.
だけど 月火ちゃんの言うとおりだ
I love her so much that it's unbearable,
あいつのことが
たまらなく好きだけれど
but what I feel for her isn't love.
でも この気持ちは恋じゃないな
Red Scene
Animation Number "None"
This is much more than love.
（暦）
もうとっくに 恋を超えていた
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Hanekawa
Myahahahaha
Love
Vampire
Hanekawa
Love
Meddlecat
Hanekawa
Love
Myahahahaha
Vampire
Meddlecat
Hanekawa
Love
Myahahahaha
Vampire
Hanekawa
Love
Myahahahaha
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Far from wanting to be with her forever...
一生 一緒にいたいどころか
I actually want to die for her sake.
だって僕は 羽川のために
死にたいって思ってるんだもん
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
（旧キスショット）
予告幻聴じゃ
Here's your preview hallucination.
Thank you for buying so many copies of volume one!
We!
Are the Fire Sisters!
不死身の生き物
というわけではないにせよ
Granted, it's not a truly immortal being,
but isn't it impressive that planarians can recover no matter how often they are cut apart?
刻んでも刻んでも再生する
プラナリアというのは
We finally settled it.
Meow
あれ 大したもんじゃのう
It would be quite disastrous if the same went for vampires.
もっとも 吸血鬼が
ああいう再生をしたりしたら
What? What's wrong, Brother?
Hold on!
えらいことじゃがの
腕をもがれたら
体からは腕が生えて
If their arms were ripped out, an arm would grow back from the body.
What?! I want to take a photo
now that I have the chance!
Tap Tap
A body would regrow from the arm, and there'd be two of them.
腕からは 体が生えて
２人になってしもうての
And just like that, the entire world would be buried in people like my master and I.
Twinkle
I just want to relieve
myself of my frustration
if I don't get to see a high school girl
in her underwear with cat ears!
You're the worst!
あっという間に
わしとか我が従僕とかで
世界が埋まるぞ
Next time. Tsubasa Family, episode 4.
Next Time
Tsubasa Family Part 4
次回「つばさファミリー 其ノ肆(そのよん)」
How many vampires would we have split into this episode?
今回だけで何人に増えるかのう？
Huh? Where am I?
Now he can't do harm.